# davis allen

## software engineer

#### ABOUT

I'm a software engineer with a background in game design and project management. I bring solid technical chops and good design sensibilities to bear on the task of building engaging, compelling and fun experiences, in code. I can work through the entire product lifecycle, from initial conception and prototyping to implementation, through to delivery and deployment. I love turning deep, complex systems into simple, elegant, intuitive experiences. If it puts a smile on someone's face or makes someone's life easier, I will enjoy building it.

#### SKILLS

#### Languages

- Javascript, Python, Ruby, Java, C#,
- HTML, CSS, SQL

#### Frameworks, etc.

- Rails, Spring, keras
- Unity + Unreal Game Engines
- Arduino (Processing)
- Agile dev methodologies / project management

#### CONTACT

973.747.4916 davis@davisallen.com davisallen.com github.com/Davis-B-Allen linkedin.com/in/davisallen/

#### SELECTED EXPERIENCE

#### Web Developer

Independent Contractor / 2016 to Present

- Worked on a variety of dynamic web applications (mostly Ruby, Rails, JS)

#### Game Designer / Producer

bMuse, LLC / 2012 to 2016

- Led Game Design and Production on a variety of mobile games and connected toy projects
- Drove product development, from early-stage prototyping through the full product development cycle
- Sample of titles shipped: Transformers: Battlemasters, Hess Tractor Trek, Nerf Cyberhoop

#### Full-Stack Developer

YouAre.TV / 2010 to 2012

- Worked as a full-stack developer on two web projects at NY-based startup: a college-exclusive social network and a real-time streaming video / interactive television platform.
- Worked primarily with Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Flash / Flex 4, Node.js, socket.io, Wowza Media Server

### SELECTED/RECENT PROJECTS

#### dstrct

digital game about gerrymandering

- web + android
- java, javascript, node.js, express, socket.io

#### tweet analyzer

sentiment analysis project using deep learning to classify sentiment of tweets

- python, tensorflow, keras

#### EDUCATION

#### CUNY, Hunter College

Master's, Computer Science, 2020 (expected)

- Completed all coursework, GPA: 4.0
- Currently completing Master's project

#### McGill University

Bachelor's, Physics, 2010

- Major: Physics; Minor: Economics